<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Bucharest</string>

    <!-- The name of each category that will be displayed on the tabs -->
    <string name="firstTab">Home</string>
    <string name="secondTab">Museums</string>
    <string name="thirdTab">Landmarks</string>
    <string name="fourthTab">Parks</string>
    <string name="fifthTab">Restaurants</string>

    <!-- Text on Home page-->
    <string name="headerText">Bucharest</string>
    <string name="firstPar">Bucharest (/ˈb(j)uːkərɛst/; Romanian: București [bukuˈreʃtʲ] (About this sound listen)) is the capital and largest city of Romania, as well as its cultural, industrial, and financial centre. It is located in the southeast of the country, at 44°25′57″N 26°06′14″ECoordinates: 44°25′57″N 26°06′14″E, on the banks of the Dâmbovița River, less than 60 km (37.3 mi) north of the Danube River and the Bulgarian border.</string>
    <string name="secondPar">Bucharest was first mentioned in documents in 1459. It became the capital of Romania in 1862 and is the centre of Romanian media, culture, and art. Its architecture is a mix of historical (neo-classical), interbellum (Bauhaus and art deco), communist-era and modern. In the period between the two World Wars, the city\'s elegant architecture and the sophistication of its elite earned Bucharest the nickname of "Little Paris" (Micul Paris).[9] Although buildings and districts in the historic city centre were heavily damaged or destroyed by war, earthquakes, and above all Nicolae Ceaușescu's program of systematization, many survived. In recent years, the city has been experiencing an economic and cultural boom.[10] In 2016, the historical city centre was listed as "endangered" by the World Monuments Watch.[11]</string>
    <string name="thirdPar">According to the 2011 census, 1,883,425 inhabitants live within the city limits,[6] a decrease from the 2002 census.[3] Adding the satellite towns around the urban area, the proposed metropolitan area of Bucharest would have a population of 2.27 million people.[12] According to Eurostat, Bucharest has a functional urban area of 2,412,530 residents (as of 2015).[5] Bucharest is the sixth-largest city in the European Union by population within city limits, after London, Berlin, Madrid, Rome, and Paris.</string>
    <string name="fourthPar">Economically, Bucharest is the most prosperous city in Romania[13] and is one of the main industrial centres and transportation hubs of Eastern Europe. The city has big convention facilities, educational institutes, cultural venues, traditional "shopping arcades", and recreational areas.</string>
    <string name="fifthPar">The city proper is administratively known as the "Municipality of Bucharest" (Municipiul București), and has the same administrative level as that of a national county, being further subdivided into six sectors, each governed by a local mayor.</string>


    <!-- Text on Museums page-->
    <string name="museumsName_1">"Dimitrie Gusti” National Village Museum</string>
    <string name="museumsDesc_1"> "Dimitrie Gusti” National Village Museum, Bucharest, Romania is the “museum from the heart of the capital” who opened his gates for the public in 1936. The permanent exhibition covers a 14ha area having 360 monuments, 60.000 objects in his collections and over 250.000 documents regarding the village and its traditional life in the Archive. Indoor and outdoor exhibitions attract more than 500.000 visitors annually. The Village Museum is the most visited cultural objective from Romania, opened all week long to and a trusted Romanian and European BRAND. </string>
    <string name="museumsAdd_1">Address: Şos. Kiseleff nr. 28-30, Sector 1</string>
    <string name="museumsName_2">The Romanian Peasant Museum</string>
    <string name="museumsDesc_2">  The Romanian Peasant Museum is part of the European family of Museums of Popular Art and Traditions. It is a national museum, under the Ministry of Culture’s patronage. In possession of an especially rich collection of objects, hosted in a Neo-Romanian style historical monument-building, our Museum developed a highly original museography honored in 1996 by receiving the EMYA – European Museum of the Year Award. The originality of the exhibiting style is continued in the Museum’s publications, in actions such as the Missionary Museum, the Village School, concerts, conferences and exhibition openings. </string>
    <string name="museumsAdd_2">Address: Şos. Kiseleff 3, Sector 1</string>
    <string name="museumsName_3">“Grigore Antipa” National Museum of Natural History</string>
    <string name="museumsDesc_3"> “Grigore Antipa” National Museum of Natural History is one of the oldest research institutions in the field of biodiversity and public education. It is in the same time one of the well known and highly appreciated “databases” due to the Museum’s collections, some of them valuable assets of the worldwide thesaurus. </string>
    <string name="museumsAdd_3">Address: Şos. Kiseleff 1, Sector 1</string>
    <string name="museumsName_4">The National Museum of Art of Romania</string>
    <string name="museumsDesc_4"> The National Museum of Art of Romania is the country’s prime holder of Romanian, European and Oriental art. Located in the former Royal Palace in Bucharest, it includes the National Gallery (Romanian medieval and modern art) and the European Art Gallery. Apart from numerous temporary exhibitions, visitors can also join guided tours of the former Throne Hall and other spaces of historical relevance. </string>
    <string name="museumsAdd_4">Address: Calea Victoriei 49-53, Sector 1</string>
    <string name="museumsName_5">Controceni Palace Museum</string>
    <string name="museumsDesc_5">The Museum operates inside the Cotroceni palace, a monument of late 19th century romanian architecture, which has also fused remarkably well with the medieval architecture of the Serban Cantacuzino - founded monastery of the late 17th century. Its uniqueness is granted by the intertwinement of a memory site, of a history spanning 350 years, with that of an art museum. Its halls and appartments have tremendous memorial power, as the focus is shifted not to the inherent value of the various artefacts, but to their connection with the personalities that have lived in the palace through the many years. </string>
    <string name="museumsAdd_5">Address: Bulevardul Geniului 1, Sector 6</string>
    <string name="museumsName_6">National Museum of Romanian History</string>
    <string name="museumsDesc_6">The museum is located inside the former Postal Services Palace, which also houses a philatelic museum. With a surface of over 8,000 square meters, the museum has approx. 60 valuable exhibition rooms. The permanent displays include a plaster cast of the entirety of Trajan\'s Column, the Romanian Crown Jewels, and the Pietroasele treasure.The building was authorized, in 1892, and the architect, Alexandru Săvulescu was sent with the postal inspector, Ernest Sturza, to tour various postal facilities of Europe for the design. The final sketches were influenced primarily by the postal facility in Geneva. Built in an eclectic style, it is rectangular with a large porch on a high basement and three upper floors. The stone façade features a portico supported by 10 Doric columns and a platform consisting of 12 steps spanning the length of the building. There are many allegorical sculptural decorative details. </string>
    <string name="museumsAdd_6">Address: Calea Victoriei 12, Sector 3</string>
    <string name="museumsName_7">The National Museum “George Enescu”</string>
    <string name="museumsDesc_7"> The National Museum “George Enescu” was opened in the Cantacuzino Palace, one of the most beautiful buildings in Bucharest, a historical monument and one of the European Heritage Label buildings.The sumptuous entrance, in Art Nouveau style, announces the luxury and the refinement of the époque, reunited in one of the most imposing palaces in Bucharest. </string>
    <string name="museumsAdd_7">Address: Calea Victoriei 141, Sector 1</string>
    <string name="museumsName_8">The Theodor Aman Museum</string>
    <string name="museumsDesc_8"> The Theodor Aman Museum is one of the most beautiful private residences in Bucharest, built in the year 1868 following Theodor Aman’s own designs. It is also one of the few buildings which has remained unchanged during its existence, and is the first workshop-residence in Romania.From the architectural plans of the house and exterior decorations (done in colaboration with sculptor Karl Storck) to the interior design (mural paintings, stained glass, stucco ceilings, wooden panelling in the workshop, and the house’s furniture), the house reflects Theodor Aman’s vision.The Theodor Aman Museum was opened in 1908 and is one of the oldest memorial museums in Romania. The house maintains its intimate atmosphere, gained during the Belle Époque period, and holds a large part of painter Theodor Aman’s works. </string>
    <string name="museumsAdd_8">Address: Strada C. A. Rosetti 8, Sector 1</string>
    <string name="museumsName_9">Theodor Pallady Museum</string>
    <string name="museumsDesc_9">The museum brings centre stage a core selection of paintings by Theodor Pallady. Together with over 800 prints and drawings from the artist’s Parisian years, these are part of the Serafina and Gheorghe Răut collection, donated to the Romanian state at the end of the 1960s. The collection also comprises French, Dutch, English and Spanish paintings, European furniture and sculpture and a host of various objets d’art which speak eloquently about the manner in which Romanian inter-war intellectuals tried to emulate general trends. </string>
    <string name="museumsAdd_9">Address: Strada Spătarului 22, Sector 1</string>
    <string name="museumsName_10">National Bank of Romania Museum</string>
    <string name="museumsDesc_10">Over the centuries and all over the world, central banks have combined financial activities with supporting culture, and have been holders of numismatic and art collections. This is also the case of the National Bank of Romania.The bank has set up, ever since its first years of functioning, a valuable collection of coins and works of art, while having passionate collectors as leaders; and may we remind here the founder of the bank, Eugeniu Carada, a great admirer of Romanian painter Nicolae Grigorescu, governor Mihail Sutzu, one of the originators of Romanian numismatics, and the sophisticated book-lover governor I. G. Bibicescu. </string>
    <string name="museumsAdd_10">Address: Strada Doamnei 8, Sector 3</string>

    <!-- Text on Monuments page-->
    <string name="monumentsName_1">Memorial of Rebirth</string>
    <string name="monumentsDesc_1">The Memorial of Rebirth (Memorialul Renaşterii in Romanian) is a memorial in Bucharest, Romania that commemorates the struggles and victims of the Romanian Revolution of 1989, which overthrew Communism. The memorial complex was inaugurated in August 2005 in Revolution Square, where Romania\'s Communist-era dictator, Nicolae Ceauşescu, was publicly overthrown in December 1989.</string>
    <string name="monumentsAdd_1">Address: Piața Revoluție, Sector 2</string>
    <string name="monumentsName_2">Arcul de Triumf</string>
    <string name="monumentsDesc_2">Arcul de Triumf is a triumphal arch located in the northern part of Bucharest, on the Kiseleff Road. The first, wooden, triumphal arch was built hurriedly, after Romania gained its independence (1878), so that the victorious troops could march under it. Another temporary arch was built on the same site, in 1922, after World War I, which was demolished in 1935 to make way for the current triumphal arch, which was inaugurated in September 1936.</string>
    <string name="monumentsAdd_2">Address: Piața Arcul de Triumf, Sector 1</string>
    <string name="monumentsName_3">Equestrian statue of Carol I</string>
    <string name="monumentsDesc_3">The equestrian statue of Carol I is a monument in Romania, situated in the central zone of Bucharest, on Calea Victoriei.The massive statue, cast in bronze, represents Carol I of Romania, the first King of Romania, mounted on his horse. It is a highly representative national monument, since Carol I conquered Romania\'s independence from the Ottoman Empire for the first time, in 1877 (during the Russo-Turkish War, that is known in Romania as "The Independence War"). He was also the founder of both the Romanian Dynasty and the modern Romanian state.</string>
    <string name="monumentsAdd_3">Address: Calea Victoriei 5, Sector 3</string>
    <string name="monumentsName_4">Cantacuzino Palace</string>
    <string name="monumentsDesc_4">Built in 1901–1903 for Gheorghe Grigore Cantacuzino, mayor of Bucharest and former prime-minister. After his death, the building was inherited by his son Mihail G. Cantacuzino, who died prematurely in 1929. Mihail\'s wife Maria remarried in December 1939 with music composer George Enescu. The building – known as Cantacuzino Palace at the time – hosted the Presidency of the Council of Ministers in the eve of World War II.</string>
    <string name="monumentsAdd_4">Address: Calea Victoriei 141, Sector 1</string>
    <string name="monumentsName_5">Palace of Justice</string>
    <string name="monumentsDesc_5">The Palace of Justice, located in Bucharest, Romania, was designed by the architects Albert Ballu and Ion Mincu and built between 1890 and 1895.Located on the banks of the Dâmbovița River, it houses the Bucharest Court of Appeal and the Sector 5 Court. Its last major restoration was between 2003 and 2006.The Palace has 690 rooms with a total area of 33,235 m2 (357,740 sq ft).</string>
    <string name="monumentsAdd_5">Address: Splaiul Independenței 5, Sector 3</string>
    <string name="monumentsName_6">Palace of the Parliament</string>
    <string name="monumentsDesc_6">A colossal parliament building known for its ornate interior composed of 23 sections, it houses the Senate and the Chamber of Deputies, three museums and an international conference center. The museums hosted inside the Palace are the National Museum of Contemporary Art, the Museum of Communist Totalitarianism (established in 2015)[3] and the Museum of the Palace. Though named the House of the Republic (Romanian: Casa Republicii), after the Romanian Revolution in 1989 it became widely known as the People\'s House (Romanian: Casa Poporului). Due to its impressive endowments, events organized by state institutions and international bodies such as conferences, symposia, and others take place there, but even so about 70% of the building remains empty.[4][5]</string>
    <string name="monumentsAdd_6">Address: Dealul Arsenalului, Sector 5</string>
    <string name="monumentsName_7">Romanian Athenaeum</string>
    <string name="monumentsDesc_7">The Romanian Athenaeum (Romanian: Ateneul Român) is a concert hall in the center of Bucharest, Romania and a landmark of the Romanian capital city. Opened in 1888, the ornate, domed, circular building is the city\'s main concert hall and home of the "George Enescu" Philharmonic and of the George Enescu annual international music festival.</string>
    <string name="monumentsAdd_7">Address: Strada Benjamin Franklin 1-3, Sector 1</string>

    <!-- Text on Parks page-->
    <string name="parksName_1">Botanical Gardens</string>
    <string name="parksDesc_1">Bucharest\’s fabulous Botanical Gardens were founded in 1860 with the significant financial backing of Prince Alexandru Ioan Cuza, at the time the leader of the nascent Romanian state. Completed in 1866 to the designs and instructions of Ulrich Hoffmann, they were originally in the grounds of the Cotroceni Monastery, moving to their present location in 1884. The garden, administratively part of Bucharest University’s Botanical Institute, today extends over an area of more than 17 hectares, and hosts more than 10,000 species of plants, approximately half of which are cultivated in the impressive glasshouses. Of particular note are the exotic flowers (more than 1000 are on display) and the bizarre Symphytum ottomanum, a plant which can appear to vanish without trace only to reappear up to 50 metres away. The recently renovated glasshouses are fabulous, and kids love the wide variety of strange plants inside, especially the cacti and the Venus fly traps. Many locals like to take advantage of the bargain entrance fee and use the exterior of the gardens as a park, and thus the place can often be far more full with courting couples than with lovers of more floral delights. Whatever your reasons for going, it\'s a terrific place to spend a morning. </string>
    <string name="parksAdd_1">Address: Sos. Cotroceni 32 </string>
    <string name="parksName_2">Herăstrău Park</string>
    <string name="parksDesc_2">Anyone who still thinks that Bucharest is a city of concrete and cement has clearly never been to the city’s lung, the incomparable Herastrau Park. Quite simply, this glorious park, spread over 187 hectares around Herastrau lake is one of the jewels in Bucharest’s crown, which might explain why half of the city chooses to spend its summer Sunday afternoons here. Fear not though, for so big is Herastrau that it never gives the impression of being crowded, and even on the busiest of days you will always be able to find a quiet, shady corner somewhere. If you look hard enough.</string>
    <string name="parksAdd_2">Address:  Sos. Kiseleff 32 </string>
    <string name="parksName_3">Cismigiu Gardens</string>
    <string name="parksDesc_3">The most central of the city\'s public gardens, Cismigiu is a haven of lawns, trees, flowers and lakes. Often mistakenly referred to as a park, Cismigiu is actually a large garden, first designed and laid out in 1845 by the German landscape architect Carl Meyer, but not completed until 1860. More than 30,000 trees and plants were brought in from the Romanian mountains, while exotic plants were fetched from the botanical gardens in Vienna. Highlights of the 17-hectare garden include the Roman Garden, laid out in the style of ancient Rome, and including busts of Romania\'s most famous writers, the lake, which can be explored by rowing boat in summer or skated upon during the winter, and Ion Jalea's French Memorial in Carrara marble, which commemorates those French troops killed on Romanian territory during World War I. The park has a couple of cafes, refreshment kiosks and - in summer - terraces, as well as some good, large children\'s playgrounds. It can get very busy in good weather, but it is a lovely place to spend time. </string>
    <string name="parksAdd_3">Address: Between B-dul Regina Elisabeta, Calea Victoriei, Str. Stirbei Vodă and B-dul Schitu Măgureanu  </string>
    <string name="parksName_4">Carol Park</string>
    <string name="parksDesc_4">So close to the city centre yet strangely forgotten by many, this large park was created for the Romania in the World exhibition which was held here in 1906. (The Technical Museum, to the left of the main entrance, is housed in one of the original exhibition pavilions). Designed by the French landscape artist Eduard Redont, the park is today dominated by the massive Monument to the Heroes of the Struggle for Freedom and Socialism (it stands 48m high) built in 1963 and which until 1990 was a mausoleum which housed the remains of communist leaders Gheorghe Gheorghiu-Dej and Petre Groza (it is today the site of the tomb of Romania\'s Unknown Soldier). The park offers some pleasant walks along tree-lined paths, playgrounds and terraces, and a good view of central Bucharest from the monument. </string>
    <string name="parksAdd_4">Address: Calea Serban Vodă </string>
    <string name="parksName_5">Tineretului Park</string>
    <string name="parksDesc_5">A large, mostly lovely park featuring some of the best playgrounds in the city. Divided into two parts, the main section (closest to Tineretului metro) offers a few rides for kids, trampolines and dodgems, as well as playgrounds and plenty of tree-lined avenues great for strolling. </string>
    <string name="parksAdd_5">Address: B-dul Tineretului  </string>
    <string name="parksName_6">Titan/Alexandru Ion Cuza Park</string>
    <string name="parksDesc_6">The twin Titan and Alexandru Ioan Cuza parks, in the unsexy yet perfectly safe neighbourhood of Titan-Balta Alba, have been given much love of late and are showing the benefit of millions of euros of investment. Whole terraces have been landscaped, lawns laid, playgrounds built and sports pitches placed at every turn. Look out too for the replica Maramures wooden church on the southern side of the park, on Str. Liviu Rebreanu. It was built in 1996 and has become one of the most popular churches in the city: on major religious holidays it is difficult to get close to the place </string>
    <string name="parksAdd_6">Address: Str. Liviu Rebreanu </string>

    <!-- Text on Restaurants page-->
    <string name="restaurantsName_1">the Artist</string>
    <string name="restaurantsDesc_1">Paul Oppenkamp chose to remain in Romania in 2012, after six years of repeated visits and accepted the challenge of building a concept that highlights modern cooking techniques emphasing on creativity in cooking. With an enormous amount of knowledge in the field, Paul feels privileged of the opportunities offered due to his choice to travel around the world “it is a great opportunity to experience traditional cuisine of most countries, to understand each ingredient and their influence on locals life finally understanding their culture”. The same thing happened with traditional Romanian dishes. Every time he came to Romania, his mother in law was preparing delicious Romanian dishes and he used to visit the grandmother garden in the village, the source of the ingredients.</string>
    <string name="restaurantsAdd_1">Address: Calea Victoriei 147 </string>
    <string name="restaurantsName_2">JW STEAKHOUSE</string>
    <string name="restaurantsDesc_2">Proudly presenting the uniquely flavored USDA Black Angus prime cuts, JW Steakhouse Bucharest is a contemporary styled American Steakhouse that can accommodate over 170 guests in an elegant open space and two private, more intimate dining rooms.</string>
    <string name="restaurantsAdd_2">Address: Calea 13 Septembrie 90 </string>
    <string name="restaurantsName_3">Prime Steaks &amp; Seafood</string>
    <string name="restaurantsDesc_3">This sophisticated and intimate restaurant is perfect for a romantic evening with that special someone or for an exclusive business dinner. Guests can watch experienced chefs prepare steaks and seafood dishes in a glass-enclosed open kitchen while enjoying a bottle of fine wine selected from the variety of vintages in the walk-in wine cellar.</string>
    <string name="restaurantsAdd_3">Address: Calea Victoriei nr. 63 – 81</string>
    <string name="restaurantsName_4">Modigliani</string>
    <string name="restaurantsDesc_4">Modigliani - pasta e carne is located in the heart of Bucharest, at the ground floor of the InterContinental Bucharest, with entrance from both the hotel and Batistei Street, being surrounded by a green area space and a great terrace which gives you the elegance and peace that you need for dinner, after a hectic day.</string>
    <string name="restaurantsAdd_4">Address: Nicolae Balcescu 4</string>
    <string name="restaurantsName_5">Isoletta</string>
    <string name="restaurantsDesc_5">The restaurant is typically Italian and proposes a vast culinary offer, but we are best recognized for our daily fresh fish offer.Thanks to the contacts that Mr. Viorel Nica has made, twice a week we receive fresh fish imported directly, without intermediary from the Port of Mazzara Del Vallo in Sicily.Currently Ristorante Isoletta is considered to be the best fish and sea food kitchen in Bucharest.</string>
    <string name="restaurantsAdd_5">Address: Sos. Nordului 7-9 </string>
</resources>
